<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>POST on Nicolas Cuesta</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in POST on Nicolas Cuesta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Nicolás Cuesta Quintero</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>General Binomial Models and the Cox-Ross-Rubenstein Model</title>
      <link>/post/post_six/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_six/</guid>
      <description>Pricing derivative securities has been one of the main financial problems forboth academics and practitioners. This is the price to pay for options representinginsurance claims, interest or exchange rate hedging swaps, forward prices of commodities oreven stock options for top managerial position salaries. Usually the binomial model forpricing derivatives at Undergraduate level is used to show how to price options by takingthe expected present value of future claims over risk-neutral probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear regression: behind the scenes</title>
      <link>/post/post_five/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_five/</guid>
      <description>Linear regression is one of the most powerful statistical tools currently used in the financial industry and in the data world as well. It has been the battle horse of econometricians since the very beginning and most of empirical finance is based on its methods and rely on its hypothesis. Moreover, current data scientists use it on a daily basis as one of its most important methods for supervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An OO framework for Asset Valuation</title>
      <link>/post/post_four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:23:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_four/</guid>
      <description>Usually when you price assets in a free source language such as R or Python, you get overwhelmed by tons of functions and formulas needed to price different types of assets, leaving you with huge pieces of code that seem to be disorganized and unrelated, but are meant to just one same purpose: asset pricing. In this post I drive you through a basic object oriented (OO) framework to find fair market values across different types of assets using S4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implied volatility for stock options</title>
      <link>/post/post_three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_three/</guid>
      <description>Black-Scholes formula for derivatives pricing is at the cornerstone of modern financial theory. It holds at the foundation of Long-Term Capital Management (LCTM), a hedge-fund founded in 1994 under the management of Nobel prizes Robert Merton and Myron Scholes and whose bankruptcy in 1998 during the Rubble crisis almost lead to financial panic, enforcing Federal Reserve intervention. One of its most important applications is estimating implied volatility from options market prices, which works as a benchmark for derivatives pricing and as a measure of market risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom visualizations in Power BI</title>
      <link>/post/post_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_two/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Power BI is the current leader in the Gartner Magic Quadrant for Business Intelligence, and one of its main features is its capability for reading both R and Python code. But here is the thing, usually R plots remain as static images and lack of interactivity. Say, you want to know a point in an R scatter plot what value represents exactly. In R, you can use plotly to add this characteristic to your graphs but using plotly with Power BI default R code compiler leads to an error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the IRR</title>
      <link>/post/post_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_one/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how is the Internal Rate of Return (IRR) calculated? Many of my colleagues that come from business school understand the concept and how to use it, but when we talk about its calculation all they can think about is doing =IRR(…) or =XIRR(…) in MS Excel. The problem is that the IRR is not that simple and can lead to many problems or mistaken solutions that may fool anyone with a complex cash flow that have no idea what is happening behind scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>